

CONTACT



Hanoi, VN, Vietnam 100000

SUMMARY

Motivated **PM** with more **10 years** of experience in project management, and **20 years** of experience in software development. Interprets and understands key elements of projects to identify adverse trends and take correction action. Applies knowledge of technical aspects, procurement and quality control to successfully execute project plans.

PM SKILLS

I have more than 10 years of experience in project management according to models such as **Waterfall**, **Agile**, **Scrum**. Management skills include:

- Requirement understanding
- Financial administration
- Analytical problem solving
- Proposal creation
- HR and recruitment
- Training and development
- Technology integration
- Meeting expectations
- Quality focused

LANGUAGES

Vietnamese: First Language

Tuan Nguyen Anh

EXPERIENCE

Project Manager Lotusa Software company - Hanoi, Vietnam 03/2023 - Current

At Lotusa, I participated in software development projects as a technical leader, and project manager.

Projects that I have participated in Lotusa:

- Lotusa website
- Lotusa CMS system
- Lotusa e-Commerce system

Project Manager Ominext Software Company - Hanoi, Vietnam 04/2016 - 02/2023

At Ominext, I participated in software outsourcing projects for Japanese partners, as a developer, technical leader, and project manager.

Projects that I have participated in Ominext Company:

- Hotline chat system between patients and doctors
- Screen sharing system via Browser (by NodeJS)
- Ticket management system and automatic ticketing;
- AnalisysNet2 test results management system;
- Bee Assign System: Assign staffs to take care of patients at home;
- TMES: a project on health, helping to receive and coordinate medical examination for patients

Head of Software Development OneSMS Telecommunication Company – Hanoi, Vietnam

07/2014 - 03/2016

At OneSMS, I take on the role of both Head of Development and Project Manager. Projects participated in the Company:

- Gateway SMS system: providing SMS Brandname service for businesses;
- Mobile Data Sponsor system: provides Data Topup service for businesses to add data for subscribers of customers or their employees;
- NFC multi-function smart card system: applying NFC card technology to be used for many purposes such as payment, time attendance, parking card, door opening card, etc.;
- Onedu electronic contact book system: providing online contact book service for schools, helping schools send information to parents via SMS or Zalo.

Mobile Dev & Technical Leader AFOLI Software Company - Hanoi, Vietnam 07/2012 - 06/2014

The projects that I have participated in are games running on iOS, Android,
 Windows Phone platforms and Cocos-2D framework.

Head of Software Development Meliasoft Software Company - Hanoi, Vietnam 03/2010 - 05/2012

- At Meliasoft, I took on the role of both managing the Product Development
 Department and managing the main project of the company.
- The project I took on was developing a new version of the main product of Meliasoft: moving/convert from the FoxPro platform to .NET C# and SQL

English:	B
Upper Intermediate	
Japanese:	В
Intermediate	

Server. This is a management & accounting software, there are many parts that operate almost like an ERP system. It is a relatively large system, with a database structure of over 500 tables and over 1000 Stored Procedures and Functions.

Developer, Technical Leader, PM FPT Software Company - Hanoi, Vietnam 12/2005 - 02/2010

- When I first joined FPT Software, I took on the role of a web application developer.
- After that, I was assigned the job of a Bridge Engineer, this is the job of mediating coordination, connection and transmission between the project team at FPT and the project team of the Japanese partner. During this time, I went to Japan 3 times to work at FPT's partners, Nissen and NTT Data.
- Next, I took on the role of a Project Technical Leader, and finally a Project Manager.

Web Developer, Web Administrator Vlife-PC Computer Company - Hanoi, Vietnam 07/2003 - 11/2005

 I have played the role of a technician assembling computers for customers, and at the same time, I was also assigned to manage the Company's website.



EDUCATION

Certificate of Higher Education: IT and Japanese AOTS of Japan - Tokyo, 2009

Bachelor of Science: Programming & Economics
University of Finance and Business Administration – Hung Yen, 2003



TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Frontend (Web): Angular, ReactJS, NextJS, Java Spring, PHP, HTML, CSS
- Backend: NodeJS, C# .NET Framework, Java
- WinForms: C# and VB .NET Framework, WPF
- Database: SQL Server, Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL, DB2, NoSQL, SQLite
- Mobile App: Java Android (Flutter), iOS Objective-C, Xamarin, PhoneGap
- Mobile Game: C++ (Cocos-2D cross-platform framework)
- Cloud: Amazon Web Service (AWS), Google Cloud (Firebase Cloud Messaging)



INDUSTRIES

The projects that I have worked on are in the following areas:

- Health, medical (Japanese market)
- Accouting, ERP
- System management
- Utility
- SMS Gateway
- Mobile games